We are going to be discussing about simple, volume and drift volume.
So what is the simple volume?
A simple volume is a portion of a physical disc that functions as though it was a physical
disc preset unit.
A simple volume can consist of a single region on a disc or multiple region of the same
disc that are linked together.
So let's create a simple volume from our disc management.
So when you're on your disc management, you can see we have disc 2, it's actually a basic
disc.
So what we need to do right now is to right click and you can see when you right click
we have the opportunity to create a new simple volume, so just click on that.
And at this moment you can see it's welcome to the new simple volume wizard.
So they just click Nest.
I'm going to use all the space, the level space disc, but we can't only decide to use
for example, divide the 10 gigabytes into 2 and then use 5 gigabytes of free, so let's
just click Nest.
And there we can decide to circle over, actually give this a different drive and then click
Nest.
And now we can decide to just click this, call this, just call this this one.
And then here we have the option to do not format, we can format this, belong with the
following settings and going to be the fault, you can see we have a NTFS or FTS32 or the
REFX, we can perform it quick format and also we can enable file for the compression.
So let's click Nest and then finish.
Now a simple volume has been created.
What is at all is striped volume?
It's striped volume, which is called at all, it's also the called the REIT 0 combines and
air of free space from multiple hard disk anywhere from 2 to about 32 disk into one logical
follow.
So that is written to strip volume is inter-leveled to all disk at the same time instead
of sequin, shall we?
So now let's try to actually create a strip volume.
You can see also have I'm should this which are online and they are all both are basic
disks.
So if I write click, you can see we have the option to actually create a new strip
volume.
So let me just click, create new strip volume and then click Nest and now we have one disk.
So what you need to do is to add a second disk storage.
So we now have to disk which we can use to create as striped volume.
So just like Nest and you can decide to give this a letter E and then let me just call
this data.
And also it says we can also perform a quick format on this, let me just perform a quick
format and then click Nest and then click Finish.
It says the operation you select here will come via the selected basic disk storage dynamic
disk.
So which means that when you have to try to create a striped volume, it's going to come
via your visit data.
Because you can use a visit this totally create a striped volume.
So let me just like yes and then it's the volume is being created.
So if I go back again to my here you can see we just it's just been created.
Now we now have just one disk what is actually two which means that when you actually
copy the information to that disk, both information will be copied to multiple disk which
of course makes your information be copied to those very very faster.
Well retrieving information from that disk sometimes may be slower, but copying information
to that disk is more faster.